ILGWU David Dubinsky Memorabilia 5780/002 MB
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU David Dubinsky Memorabilia
1964-1975
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Dubinsky, David
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/002 MB
3 cubic feet
3 linear ft.
Memorabilia.
This collection consists of memorabilia, originally received with collection 5780/002. Scrapbooks, awards, buttons, badges, union dues books, passports, and correspondence are some of the items included in this collection.
6568871
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 19, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, July 28, 2015
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780/002: ILGWU David Dubinsky Correspondence 5780/002 AV: ILGWU David Dubinsky Audio Recordings 5780/002 P: ILGWU David Dubinsky Photographs 5780/136: ILGWU David Dubinsky Scrapbooks 5780/179 MB: ILGWU David Dubinsky Memorabilia 5780/179 P: ILGWU David Dubinsky Photographs
Labor leaders; Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982; American Federation of Labor
6568871
- David Dubinsky, Doctor of Humane Letters, At the 78th Commencement Temple University, June 11, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Scrap book David Dubinsky Student Center, Dedication Ceremony, Fashion Institute of Technology, October 22, 1975. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Two scrap books with same heading on the front each with slightly different contents. "David Dubinsky in recognition of Twenty Year achievement as Executive officer, ILGWU April 23, 1949" (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Green padded box containing star shaped medals and a green and red sash (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Book "We shall never forget", edited by Towiah Friedman (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Book "Tel-Aviv-Yafo: People and things which", edited by M. Kalir, et.al. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Red leather cover "Presented to David Dubinsky, President ILGWU" contents include City of New York Intradepartmental Memorandum, November 29, 1954; Application for a Visa (Emma Dubinsky); Draft form 1910, 1910-1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Scrap book full of correspondence by David Dubinsky (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Bard College scrap book June 16, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Scrap book full of (water color) pictures of Egyptian ships "To Mr. David Dubinskyfrom ABA Khoushy, Mayor of Haifa, December 1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Passports Emma Dubinsky 1934, 1948, 1955; David Dubinsky 1925, 1935, 1948, 1955, 1959, 1964, 1925-1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  also - Bank book; Membership cards; International Certificates of Vaccination; Pipe Club, membership card; Presidents' National Labor-Management Conference (1945); United Nations; Board of Elections; Building and Construction Trades Dept. Quarterly Working Card; Chicago Journeymen Plumbers [8 cards, 1 bank book, 1 vaccination certificate, 3 Socialist cards, 9 passports]
- Miscellaneous-- (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Coin "1 1930"; lapel pin "UAW"; lapel pin "JFTWU"; coin "Dept. of Labor United States of America"; 2 Canadian coins, too worn to easily read; Key chains 2 "Popular Price Dress Contractors Association, Inc."; tie clip "JFTWU"; Engraved (Large) souvenir coins "David Dubinsky, Award for Excellence presented by New York City Diamond Jubilee Committee, 189801973, John V. Lindsay, Mayor, Lewis Rubin, Chairman"; "Unione Mondiale ORT, Congresso Per L85 Mo Anniversario"; Print plate "Pace One Award"; Sheet of buttons/pins "Roosevelt Elector David Dubinsky"; Sheet of medals; "7th Biennial Convention AFL-CIO Guest"; Thirty-First Convention 1982 Atlantic City President"; "Catholic War Veterans Award"; Thirty-Fifth Convention 1974 ILGWU Honor Guest"; "Distinguished Guest 16th Convention UAW Atlantic City -- 1957"; "Special Convention AFL Chicago, August 11, 1955 7th Vice President"; Guest Seventh Convention NYC May 1950"; "AFL" "Twelfth Vice-President Oct. 7, 1946, Chicago"; Key with felt patch "Istituto F.D. Roosevelt"; Copper plate ""David Dubinsky Presented to our President in Commemoration of the 100th Anniversary of the Revolution of 1848, by the Italian Cloakmakers Union Local 48, ILGWU, New York 1948, E. Molisani, Mgr."
- Booklet "Presented by ILGWU Chorus to David Dubinsky, President, at 23rd Convention, ILGWU on May 3, 1937 at Atlantic City"; News clipping "David Dubinsky From the Newspaper Guild of New York for his Inspired Leadership of the ILGWU" (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Gold coin "Golden Door Award David Dubinsky 'I lift my lamp beside the Golden Door' "; Bronze coin "man depicted on front engraved on back "In Gratitude, the B.S.P. to D. Dubinsky (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Union Dues books 1911; 1915-1919; 1928; 1930-1932; 1933; 1936; 1940-1941; 1942; 1945; 1950-1951; 1952-1953; 1958-1959; 1962-1963; 1968-1969; 1974-1975; 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Scrap book "Presented to President David Dubinsky by the Locals of the Eastern Out of Town Dept. ILGWU, May, 1937" (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Padded folder with a letter of Condolence (at the time of David Dubinsky's passing) from the Senate of Pennsylvania inside. The letter is signed by the Secretary of the Senate and has an embossed Senate Seal (Box 3, Folder 7)